Briggs, Vernon, Files /4236
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Preliminary reports, final reports and executive summaries of reports to United States Department of Labor of sponsored research; also, course syllabi for classes taught. (Box 11)
  - Course Syllabi ILR 451 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Course Syllabi ILR 469 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Course Syllabi ILR 360 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Course Syllabi ILR 761 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Preliminary Draft - Apprenticeship Research: Emerging Findings and Future Trends (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Interim Report: Public Service Employment in the Rural South (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Preliminary Draft: Public Service Employment in the Rural South (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Public Service Employment in the Rural South (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Executive Summary: Labor Markets in the Rural South (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Labor Markets in the Rural South (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Appendices to Southern Rural County Labor Force Study (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Negro Participation in Apprenticeship Programs (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Publications and speeches by Vernon Briggs, 1966-2004. (Box 12)
  - Papers and Speeches Presented at Conferences and Meetings Volume 1 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Papers and Speeches Presented at Conferences and Meetings Volume 2 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Papers and Speeches Presented at Conferences and Meetings Volume 3 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Papers and Speeches Presented at Conferences and Meetings Volume 4 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Published Testimony from Public Hearings: Vernon M. Briggs, Jr. (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 2001-2004. (Box 13)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (6/16-12/31/2004) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Out 2004 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (1/1/2004 - ) (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Out 2003 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (7/1-12/31/2003) (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (1/1-6/15/2003) (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Out (1-12/2002) (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (1/1/2002 - ) (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Out (1/1-12/31/2002) (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (7/1-12/31/2001) (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (7/1-12/31/2001) (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (1/1-6/30/2001) (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Articles and papers by others (Box 14)
  - Briggs Testimony - August 29.2006 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Killingsworth, Charles C. - "How to Pay for Higher Education" (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Killingsworth, Charles C. - "Fortune's Marvelous Misinformation Man" (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Killingsworth, Charles C. - "An Overview of the Job Market for Youth" (1980) (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Killingsworth, Charles C. - "Unemployment in the United States" (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Killingsworth, Charles C. - "Unemployment After the Tax Cut" (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Gordon, Margaret S. - "US Manpower and Employment Policy" (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Lockwood, Howard C. - "Testing Minority Applicants for Employment" (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Levitan, Sar - "Manpower Aspects of the Economic Opportunity Act" (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Bok, Derek - "Reflections on the Distinctive Character of our System of Labor Law" (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Vocational Education and Reindustrialization - Rupert N. Evans (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - "Can we Afford to Employ all the Poor?" - S.A. Levitan and M. E. Park (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Congress and Presidency: Shift. Balance Congress v. Pres.: Myth and Pendulum - Levitan, S. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Levitan, Sar - "Doing the Impossible - Planning a Human Resource Policy" (1980) (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Levitan, Sar - "Unemployment and Minimum Wages in the Welfare State" (1980) (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Till, Thomas E. - "The Economy of Rural America and the 1980s: A Background Paper" (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Glover, Robert W. - "Apprenticeship in the US: Implications for Vocational Education Research and Development" (1980) (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - "Rural Labor Market Behavior and Rural Employment Policy" - Philip Martin (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Full Employment and the New Economics - Killingsworth, C. (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Hansen, W. Lee - "Labor Force and Occupational Projections" (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Killingsworth, C.C. - "Automation, Jobs, Manpower" (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Killingsworth, Charles C. - "Summary - Structural Unemployment in the United States" (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Killingsworth, Charles C. - "Unemployment and the Tax Cut" (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - "Rural Jobs from Rural Public Works" - National Rural Center, Inc. (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Kutscher: Employment Growth in the United States (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Blum: Speech on New York State's Experience with Workforce (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - A Review of CETA Training: Implications for Policy and Practice - Robert Taggart - June 25-26, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Rural Job Creation: Bruno, A.L. and Wright, L.M. (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Rural Jobs from Rural Public Works: Goodwin, Toews, Baker, Cornman (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Labor Force Statistics for Full Employment - Sar Levitan (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - A Liberal Agenda in Orderly Retreat - Sar Levitan (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Reaganomics Needs a Prayer - Sar Levitan (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - The Reagan Economic Package in Perspective - Charles Killingsworth (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - CETA Reauthorization and Lots More - Sar Levitan (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Combining Employment and Earnings Measurements - Sar Levitan and Robert Taggart (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Assistance for Trade-Affected Workers and Firms (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Dislocated Workers (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - New Economic Order; Collective Bargaining (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - "Wage-Price Policy and Alternatives" - M. Rothbaum (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - "Four Introductory Lectures on Political Economy" (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - "Four Introductory Lectures on Political Economy" (Box 14, Folder 41)
- Correspondence, 2005-2010; Annual Reports (Box 15)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (Jan-June 2005) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (July-Dec. 2005) (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Out 2005 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (Jan-April 2006) (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (May-Aug. 2006) (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (Sept-Dec 2006) (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Out 2006 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (Jan-June 2007) (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (July-Dec 2007) (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Out 2007 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (Jan-June 2008) (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (July-Dec 2008) (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Out 2008 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Incoming and Outgoing 2009-10 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Alexander Citan 2004 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Employment at University of Texas (1964-78) (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Employment at Cornell University (1978-2007) (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Annual Reports from University of Texas (1964-78) (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Annual Reports from Cornell University (1978-1990) (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Annual Reports from Cornell University (1990-1999) (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Annual Reports from Cornell University (1999-2008) (Box 15, Folder 21)
- Correspondence; Contracts; Publications; College Papers (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, 2015-2016 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Contract: Johns Hopkins University Press, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    January 1967
  - Contract: Macmillan Company, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    July 1968
  - Contract: U.S. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    June 1970
  - Contract: Sage Publications, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    December 1971
  - Contract: U.S. Department of Labor, 1971-1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    Southern Rural Labor Market Study
  - Contract: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    May 1972
  - Contract: Johns Hopkins Press, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    November 1972
  - Contract: Charles Merrill Publishing, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    May 1973
  - Contract: U.S. Department of Labor, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    July 1973
  - Contract: Georgia State and U.S. Department of Labor, 1973-1975 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    Rural Poverty Study.
  - Contract: National Academy of Sciences, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Contract: Sage Publications, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    December 1975
  - Contract: University of Texas Press, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    March 1976
  - Contract: D. A. Lewis Associates, 1976-1977 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Contract: Skeptic Magazine, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    March 1977
  - Contract: Praeger Publishing, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    April 1977
  - Contract: U.S. Civil Rights Commission, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    May 1977
  - Contract: National Council on Employment Policy, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    October 1977
  - Contract: University of Mississippi, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    Amendment to contract. September 1978
  - Contract: U.S. Department of Labor, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    November 1978
  - Contract: Richard D. Irwin, 1978-1987 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    Labor Economics
  - Contract: Sage Publishing, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    February 1979
  - Contract: Center for Manpower Studies, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    Contract extension. August 1979.
  - Contract: U.S. Department of Labor, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    Grant modification. December 1979.
  - Contract: Journal of Economic Literature, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Contract: U.S. Department of Labor, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    Grant extension.
  - Contract: U.S. Civil Rights Commission, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    May 1980
  - Contract: University of Texas, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    June 1980
  - Contract: Growth and Change, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    September 1980
  - Contract: Manpower Demonstration Research Corporation, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    November 1980
  - Contract: University of North Carolina Press, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    Chapter: Unemployment and underemployment in rural areas. November 1980
  - Contract: Texas Business Review, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Contract: ILR Publications, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    Apprenticeship volume. February 1981.
  - Contract: Institute for the Study of Human Issues, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    July 1981
  - Contract: Texas Business Review, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    January 1982
  - Contract: Tennessee Valley Authority, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    May 1983
  - Contract: Journal of Economic Issues, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    November 1983
  - Contract: Johns Hopkins University Press, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 39)
    Immigration Policy and the American Labor Force. January 1984
  - Contract: U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 40)
    October 1985
  - Contract: U.S. General Accounting Office, 1985-1986 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - Contract: Journal of Economic Issues, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 42)
    August 1986
  - Contract: Science, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    October 1987
  - Contract: U.S. General Accounting Office, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 44)
    August 1988
  - Contract: U.S. General Accounting Office, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 45)
    October 1988
  - Contract: Richard D. Irwin, 1988-1993 (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - Contract: Population and Environment, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 47)
    August 1989
  - Contract: ILR Report, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 48)
    October 1990
  - Contract: M. E. Sharpe, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 49)
    March 1992
  - Contract: Regional Plan Association, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 50)
    October 1992
  - Contract: JAI Press, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 51)
    November 1992
  - Contract: American University Press, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 52)
    December 1992
  - Contract: M. E. Sharpe, 1995-1996 (Box 16, Folder 53)
    Revised edition.
  - Contract: State of California Department of Justice, 1995-1999 (Box 16, Folder 54)
  - Contract: Journal of Economic Issues, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 55)
    February 1996
  - Contract: Encyclopedia of Political Economy, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 56)
    September 1996
  - Contract: Journal of Economic Issues, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 57)
    March 1998
  - Contract: Journal of Economic Issues, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 58)
    December 1998
  - Contract: Academic Press, 1998-1999 (Box 16, Folder 59)
  - Contract: University of Miami, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 60)
    February 1999
  - Contract: TLG Media, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 61)
    February 2000
  - Contract: Questia Media, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 62)
  - Contract: Cornell University Press, 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 63)
  - Contract: M. E. Sharpe, 2001-2003 (Box 16, Folder 64)
    Third edition.
  - Proposal: The Cordelia May Family Trust, 1989-1990 (Box 16, Folder 65)
  - Charles P. Larrowe: A Meteor of the Industrial Relations Horizon: The Foreman's Association of America, 1961-1962 (Box 16, Folder 66)
  - The Texas Observer: The Farm Workers Arise, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 67)
    June-September 1966
  - Address by William B. Saxbe, Attorney General of the United States, on Illegal Immigration, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 68)
    October 30, 1974
  - The Characteristics and Role of Illegal Aliens in the US Labor Market: An Exploratory Study, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 69)
  - Non-Apprehended and Apprehended Undocumented Residents in the Los Angeles Labor Market: An Exploratory Study, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 70)
    May 1979
  - Herbert Hill: The Equal Employment Opportunity Commission: Twenty Years Later, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 71)
  - Agricultural Labor Markets in New York State and Implications for Labor Policy, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 72)
    Final Report. May 1991
  - Plebiscite: Puerto Rico at a Political Crossroad, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 73)
    June 1991
  - FDR Library, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 74)
  - Response, Persistence and Resiliency: A Report on the Accomplishments of the Latino Studies Program at Cornell University, 1987 through Spring 2012 (Box 16, Folder 75)
    August 9, 1012
  - Voices: Immigration (Box 16, Folder 76)
    Issue no.4
  - The Regulation of Labor Relations by the Common Law Prior to 1914, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 77)
    Economics 308. College paper by Vernon Briggs.
  - Political Instability and Economic Development, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 78)
    Economics 350. College paper by Vernon Briggs.
  - The Contribution of Sidney and Beatrice Webb to Social Welfare, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 79)
    Economics 456. College paper by Vernon Briggs.
  - The Alleged Communist Dominated Unions, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 80)
    Economics 520. College paper by Vernon Briggs.
  - Indonesia Since 1945, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 81)
    History 584. College paper by Vernon Briggs
  - Appraisal of the Smithian Concept of Private Property, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 83)
    Economics 841A. College paper by Vernon Briggs.
  - An Appraisal of the Role of Productivity in the Marxian System, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 83)
    Economics 841B. College paper by Vernon Briggs.
  - Review: Productivity and Technical Change (Box 16, Folder 84)
    Economics 856C. College paper by Vernon Briggs.
- Case No. 94-7569-MRP, Declaration of Robert Sertich, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Reports from New York about the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986, 1987-1990 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Reports and Recommendation from California about the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- GAO report of the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Workplace Discrimination under the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Civil Rights Complaint for Declaratory and Injunctive Relief, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Case No. 94-7569 Opinion (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Case No. 94-7569-MRP, Notice of Motion and Motion for Summary Judgement, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Case No. 94-7569-MRP, The Various Applications for Issuance of a Temporary Restraining Order Re proposition 187, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Letters to Professor Vernon Briggs, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 20)
- Case No. 94-7569-MRP, Memorandum of Point and Authorities in Support of Gregorio T. Plaintiffs Motion for Summary Judgement, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 12)
- No. 94-7569-MRP, Opposition to the Summary Judgement by Plaintiff, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Case No. 94-7569-MRP, Declaration of Larry Bolton, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Case No. 94-7569-MRP, Opposition of State Defendants to Motion for Summary Judgement, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 15)
- Case No. 94-7569-MRP, State Defendants' Memorandum of Points and Authorities in Opposition to Plaintiff, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Articles about California's proposition 187, 1994-1995 (Box 17, Folder 17)
- Handwritten Notes about Proposition 187 (Box 17, Folder 18)
- News from the Senate majority Taskforce on Immigration, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 19)
- Case No. 94-7569-MRP, Defendants' Statement of Intentions Concerning Proposition 187, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 9)